Zach Schneider

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Budd Lake, NJ, 07828

Phone

(419) 376-0273

E-mail

zachary.schneider85@gmail.com

www

https://zschneid85.github.io/devportfolio/

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/zach-schneider-5151aa1

Skills

JavaScript Very Good Java **Excellent** Git Good HTML/CSS Excellent SQL <u>Excellent</u> WordPress Excellent PHP Very Good **JQuery** Very Good Bootstrap 4 Good

PROFILE Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

Work History

2018-08 -Current

Software Developer

Zip Code Solutions, Parkesburg, PA

- Developing ,optimizing and maintaining websites and applications utilizing PHP, MySQL, Javascript , and various APIs to meet the goals of 30 plus clients.
- Creating an Administrative backend so that clients can quickly update data by using databases.
- Migrating existing websites/applications to a stable,
 high-maintainable platform via AWS and WordPress.
- Analyzing requirements and designing, developing and implementing software applications for multiple websites.
- Preparing and presenting technical proposals to clients focusing on needs.

2019-11 -Current

Lead Teacher

Wize Computing Academy, Exton, PA

- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional platforms Scratch, Lego wedo 2.0.
- Keeping 15 students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Implementing lesson plans from start to finish with a Stem focused curriculum.

2016-11 -2018-03

Medicaid Billing Rep

Conifer Health Solutions, Exton, PA

- Worked on 1,200 accounts per week with great attention to detail.
- Used a wide range of Medicaid billing tools to resolve a wide range of insurance denials.
- Produced \$150,000.00 per month in company revenue.

Education

2018-03 -	Certification of Completion: Software Development
2018-05	Rutgers University - New Brunswick
	Coding Bootcamp
2004-08 -	Bachelor of Science: History
2008-05	Eastern Michigan University - Ypsilanti, MI